Michael John Eaton

Address: 1 Albany Grove, Lymm, Cheshire, WA13 9LX

Mobile: 07807764794

Email: mikejeaton@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/mikeeeaton

Summary

An enthusiastic, hardworking and reliable individual currently working as a Software Developer at PortSwigger Web Security in one of their Agile product development teams. Having achieved a first-class (honours) degree in Software Engineering from Sheffield Hallam University and obtaining over 3 years' experience working as a Software Developer in a variety of industries. This experience alongside a strong interest in application security has allowed Michael to consistently produce secure, high quality software in a range of different technologies including C# .NET, JavaScript & Java using modern development techniques such as Test-Driven Development and Agile methodologies.

Core Skills

- 2 years industry experience of full stack .NET development.
- 1-year industry experience of Java 9 development.
- 4 years' academic experience of software development.
- Security Encryption, Veracode training and vulnerability testing/analysis with Burp Suite.
- Test and Behaviour Driven Development.
- Agile Methodologies Scrum and Kanban.
- Software Design Experience with UML, use case analysis and storyboarding.
- Source Control Git & Team Foundation Services.

Technical Skills

<u>Languages</u>	Experience (Years)	<u>Tools</u>	Experience (Years)
C# (.NET Core, WPF,	5	Visual Studio	6
WinForm)		Git	4
SQL (SQL Server,	4	SQL Management	3
Oracle)		Studio	
JavaScript (ES6,	3	Visual Studio Code	2
Node.js, React,		JIRA	2
Angular)		Team Foundation	1
C++	3	Server	
Java	3	Trello	1
HTML & CSS	2	Yodiz	1
Python	1	IntelliJ	1
NoSQL (MongoDB)	1	Burp Suite	1
VB.NET	1	Professional &	
		Enterprise	

Education

- Sheffield Hallam University Software Engineering BEng (First class with honours) September 2014 May 2018.
- Lymm High School Sixth Form College (3 A Levels, 1 AS Level) September 2012 June 2014
- Lymm High School (9 GCSE's A* C) September 2007 June 2012

Recent Work Experience

Aug 2019 – Present – PortSwigger Web Security – Software Developer

In the first half of my employment at PortSwigger I joined the Technical Support Team as a Product Specialist to help understand the product and how its users interacted with it. I was involved in working with customers to optimize their ability to find and exploit security vulnerabilities in applications using Burp Suite, alongside reviewing any new BApp Extension submissions and taking ownership of the extension marketplace. I then joined the Burp Suite Professional development team and worked alongside the other developers in maintaining and upgrading existing features such as building a bespoke HTTP/2 network stack, refactoring and writing a test framework for Burp Intruder and improving the user experience by implementing a new request editor with modern features that you find in popular IDE's. Working at PortSwigger has tremendously improved my knowledge and understanding of application security vulnerabilities as I often consulted and worked alongside the research team while developing these new features who are actively finding and exposing vulnerabilities in real world applications.

<u>June 2018 – Aug 2019 – Blue Prism Group – Junior Software Developer</u>

I joined Blue Prism to enter one of the product teams helping to develop their Windows .NET application 'Blue Prism' in the quickly expanding Robotic Process Automation market. I have contributed to many different product enhancements and features including a new Robotic process-building toolbar which allows Robots to access third-party API's which was showed off at the main stage at 'Blue Prism World' in London & Orlando. Working with a team to develop a new data analytics engine to allow process managers to more easily monitor robot productivity and helping develop a brand-new product which will allow Robots to process scanned documents using OCR technology. The teams I have worked in have always been heavily Agile based (Scrum & Kanban) with daily stand-up, sprint planning & retrospective meetings. An additional role I have taken on is the 'Encryption Champion' for our Security Team in which I was responsible for being the Encryption knowledge base for my team and in this role, I took on Veracode training and then published a document which outlined all the encryption details for our product to our Sales/Marketing teams so they could easily confirm security compliance queries with potential customers.

<u>June 2016 – May 2017 – Sports Direct PLC – Junior Software Developer (Placement)</u>

At Sports Direct I worked closely with senior developers on multiple projects including maintaining and upgrading the in-house digital signage system, developing a new system to manage flash sale events across the 40+ websites that the team were responsible for and developing another new system to enable the warehouse managers to monitor the status of deliveries leaving the site for the different couriers that were contracted by the company. During my time at Sports Direct my communication and teamworking skills have improved tremendously, my confidence has improved as I regularly needed to lead meetings across the company and my technical abilities have greatly improved due to the various technologies I was exposed too during my placement.

Hobbies & Interests

Encryption – Currently developing an open-source .NET Standard library to configure and encrypt data with an Enigma machine.

Sports - Formula 1 & Football.

References

- Duncan Lowe E-Commerce Development Team Leader Sports Direct duncan.lowe@sportsdirect.com
- Dave Powell Managing Director Thrive Creative dave@thrive-creative.co.uk